<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Chris Winters Blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.cwinters.com/feeds/cwinters.atom" type="text/html"/>
  <id>http://www.cwinters.com/feeds/cwinters.atom</id>
  <subtitle>More boring geek stuff</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Winters &lt;chris@cwinters.com&gt;</name>
  </author>
  <updated>2011-08-14T22:59:21-04:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Physical precision</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/08/14/physical_precision.html" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Winters</name>
    </author>
    <updated>2011-08-14T22:59:21-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/08/14/physical_precision.html</id>
    <content type="html">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
 

 
<blockquote>The new physicality brought an unexpected element 
into the act: precision. My routines wove the verbal with the 
physical and I found pleasure trying to bring them in line. Each 
spoken idea had to be physically expressed as well. My teenage 
attempt at a magician's grace was being transformed into an 
awkward comic grace. I felt as through every part of me was 
working. Some nights it seemed that it wasn't the line that got 
the laugh, but the tip of my finger. I tried to make voice and 
posture as crucial as jokes and gags....Finally, I understood the 
cummings quote I had puzzled over in college: "Like the burlesque 
comedian, I am abormally fond of that precision which creates 
movement." Precision was moving the plot forward, was filling 
every moment with content, was keeping the audience engaged. 
</blockquote> 
 
<p>Steve Martin, <u>Born Standing Up</u></p> 
 
<!-- Tags: comedy; work --> 
 
 

<p class="align-right">
  <a href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/08/14/physical_precision.html">Permalink</a>
</p>
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Consistent work</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/08/14/consistent_work.html" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Winters</name>
    </author>
    <updated>2011-08-14T22:53:38-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/08/14/consistent_work.html</id>
    <content type="html">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
 

 
<blockquote>The consistent work enhanced my act. I learned a 
lesson: It was easy to be great. Every entertainer has a night 
when everything is clicking. These nights are accidental and 
statistical: Like lucky cards in poker, you can count on them 
occurring over time. What was hard was to be <em>good</em>, 
consistently good, night after night, no matter what the 
abominable circumstances.</blockquote> 
 
<p>Steve Martin, <u>Born Standing Up</u></p> 
 
 
 
<!-- Tags: comedy; work --> 
 
 

<p class="align-right">
  <a href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/08/14/consistent_work.html">Permalink</a>
</p>
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>That reminds me...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/05/18/that_reminds_me.html" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Winters</name>
    </author>
    <updated>2011-05-19T02:07:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/05/18/that_reminds_me.html</id>
    <content type="html">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
 

 
<p><img src="/images/shit_sandwich.png" width="415" height="310"/></p> 
 
<p>...I need to watch Spinal Tap again. Who are you people who 
<a href="http://www.pajiba.com/comment_diversions/the-10-films-people-most-lie-about-seeing-what-classic-movie-have-you-pretended-to-see.php">pretended 
to see it but didn't actually</a>? The mind boggles. That film 
doesn't age for me as many comedies do (Strange Brew for instance 
-- still love it, not the same experience). Other Guest + 
Co. productions are similar in their longevity. May they continue.</p> 
 
<!-- Tags: movies; fun  --> 
 
 

<p class="align-right">
  <a href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/05/18/that_reminds_me.html">Permalink</a>
</p>
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Happy anniversary!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/04/08/happy_anniversary.html" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Winters</name>
    </author>
    <updated>2011-04-08T11:05:38-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/04/08/happy_anniversary.html</id>
    <content type="html">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
 

 
<p>Eleven years ago, on a  
<a href="http://www.erh.noaa.gov/pbz/apr00.htm">blustery, snowy</a> 
Pittsburgh day, I married my favorite person. Lucky me, lucky 
us.</p> 
 
<p> 
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/cwinters/3673355282/" title="Interesting light"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3591/3673355282_dd8df1f7e3.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Interesting light"/></a> 
</p> 
 
<!-- Tags: barb --> 
 
 

<p class="align-right">
  <a href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/04/08/happy_anniversary.html">Permalink</a>
</p>
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Impressions of Pittsburgh Geek Out Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/04/08/impressions_of_pittsburgh_geek_out_day.html" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Winters</name>
    </author>
    <updated>2011-04-08T10:50:02-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/04/08/impressions_of_pittsburgh_geek_out_day.html</id>
    <content type="html">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
 

 
<p><a href="http://www.pghgeekoutday.com/">Pittsburgh Geek Out 
Day</a> on Saturday morning was very stimulating. It's an  
<a href="http://www.pghgeekoutday.com/home/open-spaces">open 
spaces conference</a>, which essentially means the sessions, and 
content within a session, are determined on the fly by the 
participants. I think this was a little disconcerting at first 
for some people but wound up working well.</p> 
 
<p>I'd guess about two dozen people attended, which IMO is pretty 
good for a first-time, Saturday-at-8:30-AM meeting. About 25% of 
the attendees were from Summa, though they didn't explicitly 
mention that. In fact, they took pains to separate their presence 
from the event, not wanting people to assume this was some sort 
of recruiting/advertising exercise. It certainly didn't feel that 
way to me -- even the 'thanks' for the free bagels/juice/coffee 
came at the very end.</p> 
 
<p>The day started with an intro to the process, then people briefly 
announced their discussion ideas before sticking them up on a 
wall, proposing a time/room for it -- there were three timeslots 
and three rooms, so only nine discussions. (The room distinction 
was mostly irrelevant.)</p> 
 
<p>I proposed three ideas with the intent that only one of them 
would probably go in because lots of other people would chime 
in. But the number of sessions wasn't as overwhelming as I 
thought, and it turned out all three were on the schedule. This 
was okay, but had the downside of missing other good 
discussions. That's a normal side-effect of getting a number of 
engaged and bright people together, but being a facilitator means 
you can't use the "law of two feet" to explore another one.</p> 
 
<p>The law of two feet is a simple thing -- if you're not getting 
anything out of a discussion, nor are contributing to it, then 
you have not only the option, but the <em>responsibility</em> to move 
elsewhere. But its implications are much deeper. There's no 
second-guessing about whether a topic is interesting or useful; 
if not, people will change it or leave. </p> 
 
<p>It's exhausting for me to determine whether people are into a 
topic, or whether I'm talking too much, or not enough -- my 
social antennae are stunted or something. So I found this a 
wonderful constraint. It also strikes me as very <em>adult</em>, as in 
you're treating your discussion colleagues as adults by allowing 
them to make their own decisions.</p> 
 
<p>The topics I attended weren't earth shattering, but wandered into 
pretty meaty areas. The first was on managing distributed teams, 
ostensibly with agile but we wound up discussing communication 
and management problems in general, how different personalities 
affect what you need to do, and a topic ('Cognitive Systems 
Engineering') that I want to learn more about. There were only 
three people in this one, but I felt like we could have talked 
for another hour or two, easily. (More with beer.)</p> 
 
<p>The second was on 'continuous deployment', a topic I'd 
proposed. We spent a good bit of time on a couple of concrete 
problems, which was excellent because it grounded the 
discussion. One of the conclusions I had reinforced was that, 
even if you cannot do continuous deployment, the act of trying to 
create the process (lots of automation and streamlining) has good 
results. Only four people in this one.</p> 
 
<p>The last was on sharing technical and domain knowledge with your 
team, though it really focused on the former. About 12 people in 
this one, a lot of it around getting people up to speed (code 
reviews/desk checks seemed to be the most mentioned method). </p> 
 
<p>Overall, the day was just great. It was exhilarating talking with 
people having the combination of: experience, useful reflection 
on that experience, lack of ego, and the desire to learn more. I 
look forward to more.</p> 
 
<!-- Tags: pittsburgh; openspace; conference --> 
 
 

<p class="align-right">
  <a href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/04/08/impressions_of_pittsburgh_geek_out_day.html">Permalink</a>
</p>
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>One of the things they don't tell you...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/04/08/one_of_the_things_they_dont_tell_you.html" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Winters</name>
    </author>
    <updated>2011-04-08T10:36:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/04/08/one_of_the_things_they_dont_tell_you.html</id>
    <content type="html">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
 

 
<p>(At least for me.) When you become a parent, many stories you 
hear about kids just cut through all your cynicism callouses and 
hit your emotional core in nothing flat.  
<a href="http://www.prx.org/pieces/37745-moth-radio-hour-1">This 
story</a> from Anthony Griffith just had me crying in a public 
place.</p> 
 
<p>I am not a praying person. But I do recognize my immense good 
fortune, and I'm thankful for it.</p> 
 
<!-- Tags: children; death; cancer --> 
 
 

<p class="align-right">
  <a href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/04/08/one_of_the_things_they_dont_tell_you.html">Permalink</a>
</p>
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Furniture churn</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/04/03/furniture_churn.html" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Winters</name>
    </author>
    <updated>2011-04-03T20:54:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/04/03/furniture_churn.html</id>
    <content type="html">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
 

 
<p>Lots of furniture churn today.</p> 
 
<p><b>Out</b>:</p> 
 
<ul> 
  <li>Dining room table and six chairs</li> 
  <li>China closet</li> 
  <li>Dining room light fixture (the first one I put up in the 
  house, one of the few handy things I can do)</li> 
  <li>Corner desk and chair (from the attic)</li> 
  <li>Sofa table and side table (from the attic)</li> 
  <li>Mica table lamp (from the attic)</li> 
</ul> 
 
<p><b>In:</b></p> 
 
<ul> 
  <li>Dining room table and four chairs (two left to 
  assemble)</li> 
  <li>Dining room light fixture (should be arriving Monday or 
  Tuesday)</li> 
</ul> 
 
<p>This is a pleasing imbalance.</p> 
 
<p>More to come -- writing, not furniture. It's been missing for 
a while, in more ways than one.</p> 
 
<!-- Tags:  house; furniture; writing --> 
 
 

<p class="align-right">
  <a href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2011/04/03/furniture_churn.html">Permalink</a>
</p>
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hiring two Java developers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2010/12/22/hiring_two_java_developers.html" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Winters</name>
    </author>
    <updated>2010-12-22T16:09:29-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2010/12/22/hiring_two_java_developers.html</id>
    <content type="html">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
 

 
<p>We're <a href="http://tbe.taleo.net/NA4/ats/careers/requisition.jsp?org=VOCOLLECT&amp;cws=1&amp;rid=490">hiring two Java developers</a>  
to <a href="http://www.accunurse.com/">my team in Pittsburgh</a>!</p> 
 
<p>Some non-HR skinny about us:</p> 
 
<ul> 
 
 <li>We are a small and empowered team. There is no committee 
 that decides whether you can start using Google Guava to make 
 things better.</li> 
 
 <li>We get to do meaningful things -- this is not "shovel CRUD 
 onto the web" type of work. We change the lives of people living 
 and working in skilled nursing facilities.</li> 
 
 <li>Java experience is a must. Yes, you can learn a language 
 really quickly, but that's the easy part. Absorbing the 
 libraries and the ecosystem takes a lot of time.</li> 
 
 <li>We have a lot of work to do, but we don't burn ourselves out 
 doing it.</li> 
 
 <li><p>You will probably[1] have a leg-up if you've got any of the 
 following:</p> 
 
  <ul> 
    <li>some UI design and implementation chops,</li> 
    <li>deep understanding of JavaScript the language,</li> 
    <li>use of Spring in anger (double word score for 3.0),</li> 
    <li>knowledge of healthcare data interchange (HL7),</li> 
    <li>working knowledge of unix systems.</li> 
  </ul> 
 
 </li> 
</ul> 
 
<p><a href="mailto:chris@cwinters.com">Let me know</a> if you're 
interested, or if I can fill you in on more details.</p> 
 
<p>[1] Speaking for myself and not for the rest of the potential 
interviewing team...</p> 
 
<!-- Tags: accunurse; hiring; pittsburgh; java --> 
 
 

<p class="align-right">
  <a href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2010/12/22/hiring_two_java_developers.html">Permalink</a>
</p>
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Small ttree config change fixes site</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2010/12/17/small_ttree_change.html" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Winters</name>
    </author>
    <updated>2010-12-17T12:36:50-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2010/12/17/small_ttree_change.html</id>
    <content type="html">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
 

 
<p>When I got my new laptop I reinstalled a bunch of perl 
modules, tending to do it on an as-needed basis vs the autobundle 
reload. ("What bothers you about that, the ease, the 
convenience...?" Anyway.) And it loaded a new version of the Template 
Toolkit. Apparently between the version on my old laptop and this 
one a number of changes had been made to <tt>ttree</tt>, which <a href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2008/07/08/new_site.html">generates 
this site</a>. And when I ran my publishing script it dutifully 
generated the Atom feed, put the new post on the front page, 
and uploaded it to the site.</p> 
 
<p>But I got an email from someone that the actual permalink 
resulted in a 404. A little closer looking found that <tt>ttree</tt> 
wasn't generating my files! I vaguely remembered having to patch 
ttree and looked around for a post on that, no luck. Turning on 
verbose mode ('verbose = 2') in <tt>ttree.cfg</tt> showed this:</p> 
 
<pre class="sourceCode"> 
cwinters@abita ... $ ttree -f ./ttree.cfg 
ttree 2.9 (Template Toolkit version 2.22) 
 
      Source: content 
 Destination: site 
Include Path: [ templates ] 
      Ignore: [  ] 
        Copy: [ \.(css|js|html|xml|atom)$, ^robots\.txt$ ] 
      Accept: [ \.txt$ ] 
      Suffix: [ txt =&gt; html ] 
     Summary:  
            0 files processed 
            0 files copied 
            0 directories created 
            2 files skipped (not modified) 
           21 files skipped (ignored) 
</pre> 
 
<p>Hmm... that number of files skipped is really low. A little 
more checking revealed that I needed to explicitly specify 
recursive behavior, with 'recurse = 1'. Everything is now as it 
should be, and now that I don't need to patch <tt>ttree</tt> 
no more surprises should pop-up.</p> 
 
<!-- Tags: cwinters.com; templating --> 
 
 

<p class="align-right">
  <a href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2010/12/17/small_ttree_change.html">Permalink</a>
</p>
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Off delicious...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2010/12/17/off_delicious.html" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Winters</name>
    </author>
    <updated>2010-12-17T10:51:34-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2010/12/17/off_delicious.html</id>
    <content type="html">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
 

 
<p>Given <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/12/16/is-yahoo-shutting-down-del-icio-us/">recent 
news</a>, my bookmarks are now going into pinboard. Here are the 
details:</p> 
 
<ul> 
  <li>Username: cwinters</li> 
  <li><a href="http://pinboard.in/u:cwinters">Web page</a></li> 
  <li><a href="http://pinboard.in/rss/u:cwinters">RSS</a></li> 
</ul> 
 
<p>Unlike some others I'm not that upset about delicious going 
away. I liked it and used it extensively (5600+ bookmarks since 
April 2004), but it's a commodity. The fact that they made the 
bookmarks so easy to export in a standard format speaks to this 
as well.</p> 
 
<p>An interesting aspect of the delicious hubbub is trust. Even 
if Yahoo sells the service to someone else, sufficient trust has 
been lost that people aren't likely to come back. Cloud services 
like this feel more susceptible to losing trust than apps housed 
locally. The ease of using the service also means it's easy to 
use a competing service, as long as you can move your data -- 
particularly one as lightweight as delicious. Is the same true of 
a hosted electronic medical record? Probably not to the same 
degree, but trust still something vendors have to zealously 
protect.</p> 
 
<!-- Tags: bookmarks; cloudcomputing --> 
 
 

<p class="align-right">
  <a href="http://www.cwinters.com/blog/2010/12/17/off_delicious.html">Permalink</a>
</p>
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
